# **Emmanuel Kuye**

I am passionate about application software testing!

Web, Mobile Devices, Enterprise Solutions, and Web Services;

My philosophy is build it, break it and then rebuild it better.

I love finding bugs, providing detailed reproducible steps and managing the entire quality process of a software development team. I use automated software testing tools to automate repetitive testable use cases, find bugs, provide detailed reproductive steps and perform scheduled regression tests. I perform functional tests, performance tests, regression test, load, manual, and stress test also write test cases and scenarios. I manage multiple unrelated software development projects using best PM tools to track progress, manage stakeholder expectations and provide timely feedback. I have worked on numerous projects some of which are listed below.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Softcom — Senior Software Quality Assurance Engineer

July 2020 - Present

Functional testing employing exploratory and test scripts. API tests automation with Postman/Newman, RestAssured, SoapUi and JMeter. UI Test Automation on web applications and Mobile applications with Selenium, Cypress, CodeceptJs

Develop & Automate end to end tests, Communicate with stakeholders

Implementation of reporting tools to constantly track test runs and generate reports.

### One-Finance — Senior QA Engineer - Automation

February 2020 - May 2020

Develop & Automate end to end tests using the test framework. Communicate with developers and PMs to enhance Acceptance Criteria and create test cases. Perform API testing using Postman, Rest-assured and use Kibana to track errors. Create supporting QA documentation for new features. Produce test plan for any feature under test.

# **Guaranty Trust Bank** — Quality Assurance Engineer/ Test Automation Specialist

July 2019 - February 2020

Automate QA test process of software at API level to ensure 98% up -time of the internet banking, mobile banking and other banking service platforms; web and mobile application automated tests improving them from the manual process that was done hitherto also setting up Load test rigs using VM's for Performance Testing in Jmeter for the core -banking application. I was also tasked with training and leading of members of the QA team on automation how-to's and best practices when it comes to QA and test automation

## Tivas Technologies — Software Engineer in Quality

August 2016 – June 2019

Automate test process of software's both web and mobile application thereby reducing the time by 60% it took to manually test. Test and ascertain quality assurance and user acceptability test ensuring they meet the client's specification, practically split larger risks into smaller, easily recognizable and readily-manageable risks.

Plot 2, Adekunle Kuye Street, Aguda, Surulere (234) 81000 67519 <a href="mailto:kuyeemmanuel@rocketmail.com">kuyeemmanuel@rocketmail.com</a> <a href="mailto:www.linkedin.com/in/emmanuel-kuye">www.linkedin.com/in/emmanuel-kuye</a> <a href="http://kuyr.github.io">http://kuyr.github.io</a>

#### **TECH STACK**

- Python
- Appium
- Selenium
- Java
- Protractor
- IMeter
- Postman/Newman
- Cypress
- CodeceptJS
- Maven
- TestNG

## Addax Petroleum Company, MIS Attaché (industrial training)

January 2014 - July 2014

I worked with the MIS team at different sub teams; Information Migration, Hardware Troubleshooting and Repairs, Presentations and Workshop Setup, Workstation Setup, Server Installations.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Covenant University**, Ogun State, Nigeria B. Eng. Electrical Electronics Engineering

August 2010 - December 2015

Ladder Logic (PLC), Computer and Communication in Power Systems, Project Management, Digital Signal Processing, Industrial Electronic, Computer Architecture, High Voltage Engineering. I designed, engineered and evaluated a 5kva dual powered inverter system.

### **PROJECTS**

- NPay web app (users and admin); fully automating the E2E test of the web app using cypress and communicated test results and metrics to the concerned stakeholder.
- Eze Wholesale; fully automating the E2E test of the web app using cypress and APIs using Newman also set up an automated reporting CI server with Jenkins and a linux server to send tests reports monitors to a slack channel at multiple times in the day.
- Carbon iOS Mobile App; fully automating the E2E test of the mobile app using Appium and Java.
- DrOHealth; an on-demand health and doctors application, I carried out quality analysis and testing of the admin portal, doctors portal, android and iOS applications.
- Gravitas PMO; an ERP (enterprise resource planning) software, with a CRM module. I strongly encourage stakeholders to think proactively and communicate about risks throughout the entire project, carried out tests and ensured the users requirements were met.
- Trustbond Mortgage Bank mobile application (formerly Intercontinental Homes Savings and Loan Ltd) Ascertained the high quality of the mobile app and admin portal. Ensured the application met all requirements put forward by the bank.
- DSVRT (domestic & sexual violence response team) for the Lagos state govt. A reporting platform for abuse, assault, rape and other domestic violence related issues. It is a highly sensitive platform that pays a lot of emphasis on a choice of anonymity. There are three channels I was required to test on. The USSD;
   \*6820#(mtn/airtel), SMS send help to 6820 and also the online reporting tool on the website.
- Tutoring of undergrads, on the python programing language.
   (volunteer work)